welcome to meditating with john vervicky
we will live stream the rest of this
week
until uh friday and then we will switch
to a weekly schedule because we're going
back to school and to work as part of
stage three reopening
the discord server will continue to have
daily meditation
sets and we will meet beginning
september the 12th
from 10 a.m to 11 a.m eastern time
for a new lesson and we'll continue that
until we are done the wisdom of my
patient course
if you're joining us for the first time
don't be put off by what i just said
there are lots of lessons and sits
recorded i think we're on like day
109 so please go to the description
find the links do lesson one start
doing uh two or one or two lessons every
week
that meet on the discord server uh with
the senior
to continue to integrate yourself into
the meditation practice
and into a contemplative and meditative
community
or senga
at the end of this session there will be
a q a
uh please limit your questions at that
time to any
anything from the entire ecology
practice either eastern
or western uh western traditions for
more general
q a please come to the live stream
general q a which we hold
every third friday of the month at 3 pm
eastern time
on youtube so i think that's everything
um uh to mention uh
yesterday i imagine for some of us
it was for me uh was challenging about
the
orientation but i was also appreciative
in both the senses
about the sense of valuing and gratitude
and also the sense of understanding um
how many people were reframing this as
a positive stage of transformation of
growth
uh that exemplifies the kind of
aspirational addictivity
uh that we've been talking about
throughout this course and so
i congratulate many of you
on coming to this realization and i
encourage
that it is shared and uh
and edified so thank you very much for
that everyone
and once again thank you for everything
we have built
together and remember this isn't ending
we're going to continue the lessons
saturday mornings 10 to 11
eastern time all right so
let's set ourselves up get ourselves in
position
um we will begin the chanting then we
will go into the silent sit
and then we will have some time for
questions we will all begin together
when i say begin
let's begin
[Music]
one
on
[Music]
one
on
[Music]
one
only
[Music]
one
begin your silence
you
slowly come out of your practice
trying as best you can to integrate what
you cultivated in your practice
with your everyday consciousness
cognition character and communitas
perhaps by reciting the five promises
we have time for some questions
so it looks like um there are no
questions for today
um i will be doing a review
of philosophical contemplative
companionships on friday
um i asked for your patience on that day
because while i'm doing the review
we will also be working with some of the
new technology we've been trying out
so we can make use of two cameras
and so that will also be trying that on
friday now we're making use of that so
we can make
the lesson sessions that will start
happening on
uh september the 12th at 10 am eastern
time we can make those lesson sessions
uh run more smoothly so i want to thank
my beloved son jason who's behind the
scenes making everything work today
i want to thank you all for joining your
attention and your commitment to your
care
please subscribe to this video to the
channel to be
notified of the next video you'll find
links to the lecture series awakening
and meeting crisis and links to
the dialogue series voices with raviki
we are planning to release a new series
this friday called untangling the world
not
of consciousness wrestling with the hard
problems of mind and meaning
and then down the road there will be a
series the elusive self
and of course um a series that is
working very hard on to be comparable to
awakening from the meeting crisis called
after socrates
and many of you are familiar with some
of that content will be in this series
because of the work we've been doing
together on the
work and play we've been doing together
in the wisdom of hypatia
please invite others who might benefit
by sharing this series
it's very important now very important
now that we join the discord server
i'm going to try and go sometimes to the
discord server i can't make any promises
now because my schedule
is still in flux you will be able to
practice sitting there they said twice
they do the movement practices
they do alexa devina practice group
version they will be homing
philosophical contemplative
companionships um which i think will
just be
a rich uh resource and reservoir
for communitas and for philia sophia in
the discord community i
i am there i'll be there once a month
um on the last monday of the month from
6 30 to 8
to the general q a
please remember that
continuity of practice is more important
than your quantity of practice
don't hold yourself to a a standard of
harsh perfectionism
but a virtuous friendship epicurean
fellowship perhaps
is a good way of thinking of it because
there is no
enemy worse than your own mind and body
but there's no friend
no ally no true companion
on the way better than your own mind and
body
you lamps unto yourselves to each other
see you tomorrow take good care everyone
you